Astrid Marisela Castro Isturiz

28 Steeple Drive. Salford, M5 4SB | (+44) 7857776118 | astrid1castro@gmail.com

Network Engineer / Infrastructure Architect

About me

A highly qualified IT Professional with experience in the engineering, administration and support of information systems. In my academic and professional life I have worked on a variety of projects that include the design, analysis, optimisation, and documentation of LAN, WAN, WLAN, VoIP, and several other network systems. Strong written and verbal communication skills. Ability to explain technical issues clearly and excellent organisational skills to prioritise tasks.

Experience

GRADUATE IT SUPPORT ENGINEER | CORPORACION WIMAC SYSTEMS, C. A. | MARCH 2013-OCT 2013

- · Providing an optimisation of the company data network in line with its growth in the last 2 years. Proposing the use of new network equipment such as: router, network UPS, higher capacity switches, virtual servers, among others.
- · Undergraduate final project based on the design of an Interactive Classroom (using Interactive Whiteboards) for training the company staff, including its educational platform (using Moodle as the software to accommodate the suite of programming courses required in the training and Zoho Corp for administration), and a data network to access it from any geographic location (remote access).

BIDS AND PROPOSALS ASSISTANT | CORPORACION WIMAC SYSTEMS, C. A. | JUL 2012-OCT 2012

- · Gathering requirements from customers and sales team in order to create an appropriate service solution (cost-effective, deliverable, and customer-tailored).
- · Providing support on the preparation of technical solutions within IT Department.

SERVICE ENGINEER INTERNSHIP | INGENIERIA INUSUAL | JUL 2008-SEPT 2008

- · Working at Level 1: diagnose software faults for both CDMA and GSM lines, and carry out software repairs (backup and flash). If no software fault is found, effectively pass on to a Service Engineer working at Level 2.
- · Working at Level 2: diagnose hardware faults and carry out hardware repairs, if possible.

Education

MSC IN DATA TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND NETWORKS | SEPT 2014-PRESENT | UNIVERSITY OF SALFORD

- · Focused on the Architecture and Design of Network Technologies.
- · Earned the Vice Chancellor's Excellence Scholarship, which is the University top award only given to the highest achieving students.

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, MAJOR IN COMMUNICATIONS | SEPT 2008-DEC 2013 | CENTRAL UNIVERSITY OF VENEZUELA

- · Focused on Data Networks and Radio Frequency Communications
- · Completed studies in the expected time
- · Ranked 3 out of 23 students in the graduation

Skills

TECHNICAL

CCNA, Cisco Packet Tracer, Qualnet, C++, Matlab, Moodle, Zoho. Office applications: Access, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Publisher, Project, and Visio

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native English: Proficient